artistdata.com 2018-09-03

# Sonicbids

## Privacy Policy

Last Updated: May 21st, 2018

### Introduction

Your privacy is important to us. The Sonicbids Privacy Policy describes what data we collect from you, the purpose for collecting the data in conjunction with the Sonicbids Sites and Services, how we share, process, and manage your Personal Data, and your rights associated with your data.

This Privacy Policy applies to www.sonicbids.com, blog.sonicbids.com and discover.sonicbids.com (together, " Sonicbids "). It explains how we collect information from users of Sonicbids, and how we use such information. Your use of Sonicbids constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. Please also read our Terms of Use, which govern the basic operation of Sonicbids. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use, you should immediately stop using or visiting Sonicbids.

### 1\. The Information We Collect and Use

  * Sonicbids collects Personal Data that you voluntarily provide us, when you register for Sonicbids, create an EPK , or create an promoter profile. We also collect Personal Data when you sign up for email newsletters or alerts on Sonicbids. Personal Data may contain your name, email, contact information, your location, as well as other information you provide to Sonicbids.
  * Sonicbids collects billing information when processing payment on Sonicbids.com in conjunction with applying to gigs and subscribing for membership.
  * Sonicbids logs your visits and use of Sonicbids, such as when you view or click on content, gigs, or ads, perform a search, or apply for roles. We use log-ins, cookies, web beacons, device information and internet protocol (“IP”) addresses to identify you, your location, and log your use.
  * Sonicbids collects and stores data about you when you use Sonicbids’ messaging platform to communicate with other users.
  * Sonicbids may place a "cookie" and on your computer when you visit a Sonicbids website. Sonicbids may use cookies to personalize your experience using Sonicbids, and to gather usage data that will help to improve the quality of the websites. There is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny, accept or delete cookies. In European Union and EEA countries, you must voluntarily consent to cookies before using the Sonicbids websites as detailed in Section 6 below.
  * Sonicbids may also obtain information about you through third party sources as permitted by applicable law, such as public databases, social media platforms, and marketing partners.

### 2\. Examples of How Sonicbids Uses Your data

  * To create an account for you to use the Sonicbids platform and services.
  * To personalize Sonicbids to give you a better experience, such as sending you targeted gig postings based on your location.
  * To respond to your requests or to manage user accounts.
  * To receive product feedback and understand our users better in order to improve Sonicbids.
  * To monitor the safety and security of the Sonicbids service and platform.
  * To use data and content about users for communications promoting membership, job posting, and engagement with Sonicbids, on Sonicbids properties and across other platforms.
  * To target and measure the performance of advertisements displayed to our users directly by Sonicbids or through third party advertising partners, on and off Sonicbids.
  * Sonicbids may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties in connection with a corporate transaction where all or a portion of our business (e.g., a portion that includes our customer lists) is sold or transferred. We also may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information if disclosure is required by law or as part of a lawsuit or government investigation or proceeding, or in order to permit us to exercise or preserve our legal rights or take action regarding potentially illegal activities or to protect the safety of any person.
  * Sonicbids reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor information, comments or other content that you voluntarily disclose and post to the Websites. Sonicbids reserves the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation, if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or the Terms of Use or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. Sonicbids also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.
  * Sonicbids reserves the right to investigate abuses on the Websites and enforce and apply this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use and any other terms or conditions applicable to the Websites or the use thereof. Sonicbids may disclose information about you to third parties if we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (1) take action regarding suspected illegal activities; (2) enforce or apply the Terms of Use; (3) comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding or other legal process served on us; (4) protect our rights, reputation, and property or that of our users or the public or (5) protect against legal liability.

### 3\. How Sonicbids shares information

Electronic Press Kit (EPK)

Your EPK is fully visible to all users on and Sonicbids, as well as publicly discoverable across the world wide web. You may deactivate your EPK or edit the information you have provided to Sonicbids at any time through your Sonicbids profile.

Messaging

The Sonicbids service allows you to share information with other users by sending and receiving messages on the Sonicbids messaging system. When you send email or message Sonicbids customer support, Sonicbids will collect and store your name, email address and the content of your message so we can provide customer support.

Posting Opportunities

When a user posts an opportunity, the notice may contain personally identifiable information. By posting an opportunity on Sonicbids, you consent to share the contents of the opportunity with other Sonicbids users, as well as make the contents publicly discoverable across the world wide web.

Other Parties Designated by You

When using the Sonicbids Service, you may share your data with other parties designated by you. For example, when applying to an opportunity on Sonicbids, you may share personally identifiable data with the recipient of your application. When inviting a Sonicbids user to apply to your opportunity, you may also share personally identifiable information with that user.

Service Providers

From time to time, we may partner with unaffiliated companies or individuals for market research, product development, quality assurance testing, or similar purposes. These companies or individuals may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but we will require by contract that they agree to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of such information. We also may subcontract with other companies and individuals to do work on our behalf; they may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but only as needed to perform their functions.

Data Processors

Sonicbids, as a data controller, collects and shares data with different data processors in the following categories:

Technology and Infrastructure: Sonicbids distributes data to processors in order to host, enable and support the Sonicbids platform and service.

Analytics and Reporting: Sonicbids distributes data to analytics platforms to better understand user behavior and track key business metrics, in order to provide a better service to its users.

Marketing Partners: Sonicbids distributes data to marketing companies to facilitate email marketing, on-site promotions, and social media, search, and display advertising campaigns.

International Data Transfers

Information, including information collected in the European Economic Area ("EEA") may be transferred, stored and processed by Sonicbids and its services providers in the United States and other countries whose data protection laws may be different than the laws of your country. We will protect your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Notice wherever it is processed and take appropriate steps to protect the information in accordance with applicable laws.

### 4\. Children Under 13

Nothing on www.sonicbids.com ("this website") is directed to children under 13 years-of-age. Sonicbids does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information on this website from children under 13 years-of-age.If Sonicbids learns that personally identifiable information from children under 13 years-of-age has been collected and/or is maintained on this website without verifiable parental consent, Sonicbids will take appropriate steps to delete such data. If you are a parent or guardian and find out that your child under 13 years-of-age has registered with www.sonicbids.com and has provided personally identifiable information on this website, you may inform Sonicbids at [needhelp@sonicbids.com](mailto:needhelp@sonicbids.com) and request that Sonicbids delete your child's personally identifiable information from its systems. After notice, Sonicbids will delete all such information.

Please feel free to send an email to [needhelp@sonicbids.com](mailto:needhelp@sonicbids.com) should you wish to share any comments, questions or advice regarding these privacy guidelines.

### 5\. Data Retention

Sonicbids retails personally identifiable information for the maximum period allowable by law, where there is a reasonable business need to retain such data. You may contact us at [needhelp@sonicbids.com](mailto:needhelp@sonicbids.com) if at any time you would like to see the Personally Identifiable Information we hold about you, or to ask us to correct or update this information, or to ask us to delete it. Please contact us if you have questions or wish to take any action with respect to information to which this Privacy Policy applies (see below for contact information).

### 6\. Additional Rights, Ruels, And Provisions For European Economic Area Users

If you are the resident of a country in the EEA, you may have additional privacy rights available to you under applicable laws. We will process your requests in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

  * Right not to provide or withdraw consent: you have the right not to provide or withdraw your consent at any time.
  * Right of access: you may have the right to access the Personal Data that you provided Us.
  * Right of erasure: you may have the right to the erasure of Personal Data that we hold about you.
  * Right to object to processing: you may have the right to request that Sonicbids stop processing your Personal Data and/or to stop sending you marketing communications.
  * Right to rectification: you may have the right to require Sonicbids to correct any of your Personal Data.
  * The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you feel the above conditions aren’t being met.

To make such requests regarding your personal data, please email the customer success team at [needhelp@sonicbids.com](mailto:needhelp@sonicbids.com) with the term “privacy” in the subject line. Please contact us if you have questions or wish to take any action with respect to information to which this Privacy Policy applies (see below for contact information).

Sonicbids is an online platform for bands, venues, promoters and other music professionals.. Users located in EEA countries may choose to enter personal data relating to their race or ethnicity, trade union membership, gender and sexual orientation when using the service. This type of information is considered to be a part of the “Special Categories of Personal Data” under Article 9 of the GDPR. By choosing to enter the above categories of personal data on the Sonicbids service, you are giving explicit consent to the processing of this personal data for purposes referenced in this privacy policy on Sonicbids.

Sonicbids has appointed a Data Protection Officer to oversee all aspects of our privacy and data security policies. If you would like to contact our Data Protection Officer, please send an email to [DPO@sonicbids.com](mailto:DPO@sonicbids.com).

In order for users from EEA countries to use Sonicbids websites, users must accept cookies. Users will be prompted at the beginning of their session to accept cookies. Users may withdraw consent by deleting their cookies from their browser settings at any time.

### 7\. Links to other Websites

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Websites. The Websites may contain links to other websites that Sonicbids may not own or operate. The links from the Websites do not imply that Sonicbids endorses or has reviewed these websites. The policies and procedures we describe here do not apply to these websites. We neither can control nor are responsible for the privacy practices or content of these websites. We suggest contacting these websites directly for information on their privacy policies.

### 8\. Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section §1798.83 permits users of Websites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [needhelp@sonicbids.com](mailto:needhelp@sonicbids.com).

### 9\. Security of Your Data

Sonicbids is committed to protecting the security of Your Personal Data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect Your personal data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We attempt to follow policies and procedures that will protect against unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information. No amount of measures is 100% secure, however. We cannot make any promises or guarantees that your data will be safe, and you provide information to us at your own risk.

### 10\. How To Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Website, please contact us at:You may contact us, for any reason, by filling out the web form at   
<https://www.sonicbids.com/support>

You may contact us by mail as follows:

Sonicbids LLC   
45 Main St, Suite 416   
Brooklyn, NY 11201

### 11\. Changes To The Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 24th, 2018. Sonicbids reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Sonicbids does not undertake to provide you with personal notice of any changes. In the event of material changes, Sonicbids will provide notice by means that are reasonable under the circumstances, such as by posting a notice on the websites. Your continued use of Sonicbids following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy means you accept those changes.
